another relationship that we have to
understand is the one between
fabrication costs and our chip area
chips are manufactured by taking a
silicon disk called a wafer and
subjecting it to a number of steps each
of these steps sort of prints some of
the aspects of the circuitry that should
be appearing on each processor and there
are a number of these steps at the end
of these steps we take the wafer and we
cut it up and each one of these small
squarish things is going to be a chip so
this is a single chip we take its chip
and we put it in a package it has pins
on it so this is what you normally see
as a chip and then we test these chips
the ones that check out fine we can sell
the ones that don't check out fine we
throw away because they don't work it is
important to understand that the
manufacturing process up to cutting the
chips up is all the same the wafer this
disk is about 12 inches in diameter it
costs thousands of dollars to put it
through the manufacturing process at
which point we hope we get a number of
working chips and very few non-working
chips but the size of the chip
significantly affects the cost again
this entire process pretty much has a
fixed cost if we have more chips here
because they're smaller we will divide
the wafer cost by the number of many
good chips that we get and our chips
will be cheaper if we have very large
shapes we will get fewer of them when we
test them especially and we will divide
this cost with fewer chips to get the
cost so it seems like the cost of a
single chip is gonna be linearly
proportional to its size but in fact
things are worse than that